# **ALEXANDER DONOVAN-LOWE**

47 Wilton Avenue, Southampton, Hampshire SO15 2HB 07399909699 - me@alexdonovanlowe.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Currently employed as the leader of a team of advocates for equality and diversity, I am also soon to be a first-class computer science graduate with a yearning to use my knowledge and skills from both my degree, and me as a person, to help change the United Kingdom for the better. For my final year project and dissertation, I chose to make an app so that people can more easily engage in protest activities and political dissidence. Furthermore, I have spent the last two years working for the student's union at my university to help improve racial equity and the awarding gap at my university. The second year of which I have spent as the manager of this team, coordinating the efforts of our 13-strong team to enact real, positive, change on campus. As a distinguished Ambassador with 2 years of experience representing Local Ethnic Minority students in the University of Portsmouth, I am culturally aware, politically savvy, and socially talented with excellent communication skills. Accomplished at collecting and analysing information from different perspectives.

### **SKILLS**

- Capable of working under stressful situations and/or with tight deadlines.
- More than competent with technology on account of my computer science degree.
- Able to work both independently, and as a team member.
- Responsible and punctual.
- Flexible problem solver.
- Able to pick-up new concepts quickly.
- Skilled at researching.
- Articulate speaker and writer.
- Personable in nature with years of customer service experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

in 07/2022

## 09/2018 - Expected Bachelor of Science: Computer Science **University of Portsmouth - Portsmouth**

- On track to get a First-Class degree.
- Elected to Course Representative for the University of Portsmouth in 2018.
- Member of several societies; IT society, Stand Up to Racism society, and Activists society.

08/2019 - 03/2020

# **Bachelor of Science: Computer Science** Göteborgs Universitet - Göteborg, Sweden

- Continuing education in Computer Science from University of Portsmouth as a placement year.
- It is worth noting that due to the COVID-19 pandemic, I was unable to attain the qualifications from the studies there.
- Received Erasmus Scholarship.

#### WORK HISTORY

10/2021 - Current

#### **Lead PGM Ambassador**

## University of Portsmouth Student's Union - Portsmouth, Hampshire

- Continued lobbying the university itself to implement a Zero-Tolerance to Racism policy, while also doing micro-implementation to get as much of that policy put into practice.
- Worked alongside staff within the university and the student's union to implement policy changes that will close the awarding gap of local minority students.
- Co-ordinated several teams to try and tackle the awarding gap and racial inequity at the university from a faculty level as a more bottom-up approach.
- Attended several "panels" where matters of equality and diversity were discussed, as an opportunity to propagate changes that the student and staff body wanted to see.
- Ensure that my team were engaged, motivated, and mentally healthy. This involved arranging psychological support for those who needed it, due to discussing their racial trauma and the impact of micro-aggressions.
- Liaised with senior management and student representatives to gather data and

research to use as evidence for policy and regulation changes.

• Worked with external organisers to further racial equity within the local community and society that the university exists in.

#### 10/2020 - 07/2021

#### **BAME Ambassador**

## University of Portsmouth Student's Union - Portsmouth, Hampshire

- Co-ordinated campaigns to get a Zero-Tolerance to Racism policy put into practice at the union, while lobbying the university to do the same.
- Won the Vice-Chancellor's Award Commendation for running student-led campaigns to help tackle the BAME awarding gap at the university.
- Communicated with students from a BAME background to discover what changes would be the most beneficial for them.
- Helped university staff create course content that is more inclusive, and less exclusive or derogatory.

## 07/2017 - 08/2019

## **Team Knowhow Mobile Expert**

## Carphone Warehouse - Portsmouth, Hampshire

- Helped the management team with the training and professional growth of other employees.
- Supported all colleagues in improving operations and resolving issues to deliver top-notch customer service.
- Delivered an exceptional level of service to each customer by listening to concerns and answering questions regarding contacts, faulty handsets, and our available services.
- Researched and updated all required materials needed for colleagues in store.
- Worked directly with mobile manufacturers to increase their sales.

# REFERENCES

## **Laurie Jones** – *Line Manager*

University of Portsmouth Student's Union – Portsmouth, Hampshire

- <u>Laurie.Jones@upsu.net</u>
- 02392 843 665

Nadim Bakhshov – Personal Tutor and Project Supervisor University of Portsmouth – Portsmouth, Hampshire

• Nadim.Bakhshov@port.ac.uk